manutd.com 2019-06-25

# Man Utd Privacy Policy | Manchester United

Manchester United is a group of companies which includes Manchester United Football Club Limited and various other entities (together “Manchester United”, "MU", the “MU Group”, "we" and "us"). For a full and up-to-date list of entities in the MU Group [please click here](http://www.manutd.com/en/General-Footer-Section/Privacy-Policy.aspx?filter=companies). This privacy policy applies to all companies within the MU Group from time to time.

 **About this privacy policy** This privacy policy explains what information we may collect about you, how we may use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights in respect of your personal data.  

Please note that our website and other digital platforms may contain links to third party websites / digital platforms which are provided for your convenience. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of our own digital platforms. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website / digital platform that you visit.

How to contact us about your personal data or this privacy policy

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or about your personal data, please email us at [privacy@manutd.co.uk](mailto:privacy@manutd.co.uk) or write to us at the following address:

Data Protection Officer  
Manchester United Football Club Limited  
Sir Matt Busby Way  
Old Trafford  
Manchester  
M16 0RA

Information we collect and what we use it for

  All personal information that we collect about you will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with applicable data protection legislation and this privacy policy. We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we obtain from our dealings with you or which we receive from other organisations, for example, our sponsors and partners.

In broad terms, we use your data for the following purposes:  
• to administer and provide products and services you request or have expressed an interest in  
• to enable us to administer any competitions or other offers/promotions which you enter into  
• to communicate with you in the event that any products or services you have requested are unavailable   
• for fraud screening and prevention purposes  
• for record keeping purposes   
• to carry out market research so that we can improve the products and services we offer   
• to track your activity on our digital platforms   
• to create an individual profile for you so that we can understand and respect your preferences   
• to personalise and improve your experience on our digital platforms  
• to personalise and/ tailor any  communications that we may send you  
• for profiling purposes to enable us to personalise and/or tailor any marketing communications that you may consent to receive from us  
• if you apply for a job with us, to process your job application

When we provide you with products or services we may collect and store any personal information that you provide to us. We may, for example, keep a record of your name, address, delivery address, email address, telephone number and payment card details. We may also record details of any disability or health needs you may have at the time of booking an event or service which will take place at the stadium or any of our other premises to help to ensure your comfort and safety. 

When you sign up with us for an online account, register to receive marketing communications from us (and/or our sponsors and partners), enter one of our competitions, fill in one of our forms (whether online or offline) or otherwise expressly provide us with your personal information, we may collect and store any personal information that you provide to us and may use it to personalise and improve your experience on our digital platforms, provide products and services you request from us, and carry out profiling and market research.

When you interact with our digital platforms, we may also automatically collect the following information about your visit.  This is primarily to help us better understand how our fans use our digital platforms to enable us create better content and more relevant communications:

• how you have reached our digital platform and the internet protocol (IP) address you have used  
• your browser type, versions and plug-ins, and your operating system  
• your journey through our digital platform, including which links you click on and any searches you made, how long you stayed on a page, and other page interaction information  
• which videos you have watched and for how long  
• what content you like or share  
• which adverts you saw and responded to  
• which pop up or push messages you might have seen and responded to  
• your subscription status  
• information collected in any forms you complete  
We may also infer your country of location from the IP address you have used to access our digital platforms and we may analyse which marketing activity led to your taking specific action on our digital platforms (e.g. downloading the app).

If you apply for a job with us, we will use the personal information that your provide to process your application, to communicate with you regarding your application and to assess your suitability for the role.  If you have any questions regarding the use, storage and retention of your personal information in relation to a job that you have applied for then, in addition to contacting the Data Protection Officer (details above), you can also contact Group HR at [hr@manutd.co.uk](mailto:hr@manutd.co.uk). 

 **News, offers and opportunities from us and our sponsors and partners (which we provide only with your consent)** We want you to be the first to know about new signings, competitions, club news, ticket availability and occasional offers from official sponsors and partners. [If you haven’t already signed up to receive these exciting benefits, please click here](https://www.manutd.com/en/SignIn?ret=https://www.manutd.com/en/myunited). You can [unsubscribe by clicking here](mailto:unsubscribe@manutd.co.uk), or by writing to us at the address above. Please note, if you don’t choose to receive this information, we will be unable to keep you informed of new services, products, events or special offers that may interest you and our ability to inform you of ticketing opportunities may be affected. An up-to-date [list of our sponsors and partners is available by clicking here](http://www.manutd.com/en/Partners.aspx) or by writing to us at the address above. If you express an interest in an offer from one of our sponsors or partners, they may let us know.  ****We may also participate in Facebook's ‘Custom Audience’ service from time to time. This service enables MU to display to you personalized advertisements when you visit Facebook’s social media platforms. It works by converting your email address to a unique number that Facebook uses to match to unique numbers that Facebook generates from email addresses of its users.   Where we use Facebook Custom Audiences, we will only include you if you have consented to receive marketing from us.  If you have given us your consent, [you can change your mind at any time by unsubscribing](mailto:unsubscribe@manutd.co.uk) or by adjusting your preferences in the preference centre.

**Disclosure of your information** In order to provide our products and services to you or to otherwise fulfil contractual arrangements that we have with you, we may need to appoint other organisations to carry out some of the data processing activities on our behalf. These may include, for example, payment processing organisations, delivery organisations, fraud prevention and screening and credit risk management companies, and mailing houses.

We may share your data with advertising networks and/or social media platforms for the purposes of selecting and serving relevant adverts to you via those networks/platforms, and to search engine and analytics providers.

We may share your data with third parties (a) if we are under a legal or regulatory duty to do so, (b) if it is necessary to do so to enforce [our terms of use](http://www.manutd.com/en/General-Footer-Section/Terms-And-Conditions.aspx), [terms and conditions of sale](https://www.manutd.com/en/help/terms-and-conditions-of-sale) or other contractual rights, (c) to lawfully assist the police or security services with the prevention and detection of crime or terrorist activity, (d) where such disclosure is necessary to protect the safety or security of any persons, and/or (e) otherwise as permitted under applicable law. 

We may share your data with [our carefully selected sponsors](http://www.manutd.com/en/Partners.aspx) and partners (as may change from time to time) but we will only do this if you have consented to receive marketing relating to our sponsors and partners or if one of the conditions in the paragraph above applies.

Some of the organisations to which we may disclose your personal information are situated outside of the United Kingdom and European Union in countries which may not have laws that protect privacy rights as extensively as in the United Kingdom. If we do transfer your personal information to other territories, we will take proper steps to ensure that your information is protected in accordance with this privacy policy.

In all instances where we disclose your information to third parties, we will ensure that your information is appropriately protected.

**Cookies** In common with many other website operators, we use standard technology called 'cookies' on our website. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive and they are used to record how you navigate this website on each visit.

For further, more detailed information on how we use cookies, [please refer to our Cookie Policy which you can read here](http://www.manutd.com/en/General-Footer-Section/Cookie-Policy.aspx).   
**  
Security of information** We take the security of your personal information seriously. When you submit your credit card details to us, we use industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to guard your information. In addition, we have security procedures in place to protect our paper based systems and computerised databases from loss and misuse, and only allow access to them when it is absolutely necessary to do so, and then under strict guidelines as to what use may be made of the personal information contained within them.

Where a password is required to access certain areas of our digital platforms, you are responsible for keeping your password secure and confidential.  Please do not share or disclose your password to any other person. **

Monitoring

** We may monitor or record telephone calls for security purposes and to improve the quality of services that we provide to you.

Please note that for your safety and security, CCTV is in operation in all of our premises which are open to the public.

If you are under 16

If you are under 16 and register for restricted areas of our digital platforms, we will collect your date of birth and retain that with your name and other details you may provide. This is so we can ensure we treat you in an age appropriate way in line with this policy. 

For so long as you are under 16 we will not send you any marketing communications, allow you to access any of our digital platform message boards, or share your details with our MU commercial partners.  However, if you have signed up to receive a product or service we may contact you about this.

Ages 13-15

If you are aged 13-15, you must first tell your parent or legal guardian that you wish to register on our digital platforms and get their consent. You must make sure that your parent or legal guardian knows and agrees each time before you:  
• email us, or ask us to email anything to you;   
• send any information to us;  
• enter any competition or game that requires information about you or offers a prize;  
• purchase an official membership; or  
• offer or agree to buy anything online. 

If you are the parent or legal guardian of a user of our digital platforms who is aged 13 to 15 we do not seek your direct consent to their registration, but we expect them to inform you and get your agreement in advance before they register and before each time they do any of the activities listed above.

Aged under 13

If you are under 13, you may only use the restricted areas of our digital platforms if your parent or legal guardian has first told us that you are allowed to do so. 

If you are under 13 and wish to register, you must truthfully tell us your name, email address, country and date of birth.  Our system will then ask you for the name and email address of your parent or legal guardian. We will send them an email so they are aware of your request and will ask them for their consent and to confirm they have authority to give that consent. We need their consent or refusal within 7 days, or else we will assume consent is not granted. Their consent can be withdrawn at any stage. 

Even if your parent or legal guardian gives their consent to your registration, if you are under 13 we still expect you to tell them and get their agreement in advance each time before you:  
• email us, or ask us to email anything to you;   
• send any information to us;  
• enter any competition or game that requires information about you or offers a prize;  
• purchase an official membership; or  
• offer or agree to buy anything online. 

If you are the parent or legal guardian of a user of our digital platforms who is under 13, they can access and use unrestricted areas but we will need your direct consent if they wish to gain access to restricted areas. If a user enters a date of birth which indicates they are under 13 when they try to register, our system will request them to provide us with your name and email address so that we can contact you to get your consent. The registration process cannot proceed without this. If we do not hear from you within 7 days, we will assume consent is refused. If you consent, we will complete the registration process. Whether you refuse or provide consent, we will update the child by email. **

  More about your information - your rights

**You may [correct or update your personal information at any time by emailing us at privacy@manutd.co.uk](mailto:privacy@manutd.co.uk) or by changing your profile on our website. Please include your name, address, date of birth and email address when you contact us as this helps us to ensure that we accept amendments only from the correct person. We encourage you to promptly update your personal information if it changes.

We will securely retain your information for as long as is reasonably necessary and in accordance with applicable law.  If you wish to submit a request that your data be deleted, please write to us at the above address.  You have the right to receive a copy of the personal information that we hold about you. Please write to us at the address above if you wish to exercise this right. 

If you have subscribed to receive marketing communications, [you can unsubscribe here at any time](mailto:unsubscribe@manutd.co.uk).

**Changes to this privacy policy**

  We aim to meet high standards and so our policies and procedures are constantly under review. From time to time we may change this privacy policy. Accordingly we recommend that you check this page periodically in order to review the latest version.

**Where to make a complaint  
**  
If you have a complaint regarding any aspect of your personal data or this privacy policy, please write to us at the above address.  If you are still not satisfied with the outcome of your complaint, you may write to the Information Commissioner’s Office at the following address:

Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

[You can also contact the Information Commissioner’s Office using their online form: https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/)

(version:26 April 2019)
